Waleed Ahmad Raza

House no B-IV 24 opposite Civil Court, Hassanabdal, Distt Attock

E-mail: raza.waleed001@gmail.com

Phone: +92-331-5314092.

Linkedin URL: in/waleed-ahmad-raza-581696ab



Objective

To seek a challenging environment to sharpen my skills through hands on experience and explore my working capabilities in an organization which recognizes and sterilize my true potential while nurturing my analytical and technical skills.

Education & Qualification

Bachelors (Year of Completion: 2018)

Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering

CGPA 3.37/4.00

Ist Division

Institute: International Islamic University, Islamabad.

Intermediate (Year of Completion: 2014)

F.S.C Pre-Engineering

Marks Obtained 857/1100

Distinction: 2nd Position in College.

Ist Division

Institute: Indus Group of Colleges, Wah Cantt.

Matriculation (Year of Completion: 2011)

Matric with Science Subjects

Marks Obtained **726/1050**

Ist Division

Institute: Saint. Paul High School, Wah Cantt.

Projects

Final Year Project:

Design and Fabrication of 3-axis CNC Abrasive Waterjet Cutting Machine.

Distinction: 1st prize in FYP Open House Competition, IIUI, 2018.

Semester Projects:

- Design and fabrication of an RC Aircraft for Design Build and Fly Competition (DBFC-XI).
- Design and fabrication of recumbent tadpole bike for Human Powered Vehicle Contest 2017, (HPVC, 2017).
- Design of HVAC System of Commercial Building.
- Automated Mechanical System through Arduino.
- Project report on maintenance of reciprocating pumps.

Experience

Summer Internships:

 National Development Complex, NESCOM (Islamabad) (19th July, 2017 –18th September, 2017)

Worked on feasibility of efficient solar system using solar panels.

Pak Elektron Limited (PEL) (Lahore)
(6th September, 2017 –6th October, 2017)

Internee at switch gear department.

Pakistan Railways Carriage Factory (PRC) (Islamabad)
(12th August, 2016 –11th September, 2016)

One month internship at various workshops of PRC, Islamabad.

Organizer:

- 2nd International Conference on Power Generation Systems and Renewable Energy Technology (PGSRET, 2015).
- Event Head Department of Mechanical Engineering Open House, 2017, IIUI.
- Organizer at Department of Mechanical Engineering Open House 2016, IIUI.
- Event Head Department of Mechanical Engineering E-Gaming Competition, 2015, IIUI.

Leadership:

- President of American Society of Mechanical Engineers, IIUI Chapter (2017-2018).
- President of American Society of Heat Refrigeration and Air Conditioning for Engineers, IIUI Chapter (2016-2017)
- President of Mechanical Engineers Alumni Association, IIUI (2017-2018)

Conferences/Trainings:

- Workshop on manufacturing system design: Introduction to mixed model assembly line sequencing and efficiency at EME College of NUST, 2014.
- 2nd International Conference on Power Generation Systems and Renewable Energy Technology (PGSRET, 2015).
- Training on PLC & SCADA from SINA Institute of Networking and Aesthetics, Islamabad, 2017.

Skills & Abilities

Personality Skills

- Communication
- Creativity
- Leadership
- Collaboration
- Time and Resource Management

Computer Skills

Simulation Software:

- Pro-e Wildfire
- Pro-e Creo
- ANSYS Mechanical
- PLC (Certified training)
- Proteus
- TORA

Programming Languages:

- C++
- MATLAB

Other Software:

- Microsoft Office
- Adobe Photoshop
- Fritzing

Languages:

- Urdu
- English

References:

- Dr. Nadeem Ahmed Sheikh Professor, Department of Mechanical Engineering, IIUI.
 - Email: nadeemahmed@iiu.edu.pk
- Dr. Syed Athar Masood Associate Professor, Department of Mechanical Engineering, IIUI.

Email: athar.masood@iiu.edu.pk